protiviti.com 2018-10-10

# Privacy Policy | Protiviti - United States

This website ("Site") is owned and operated by Protiviti Inc. ("We," "we," or "Protiviti"). This privacy policy ("Policy") describes how we may use and disclose personally identifiable information that we may collect about you through the Site ("Personal Information"). This Site is hosted on our website servers in Pleasanton, CA, USA. Personal Information will be stored through an electronic system of Protiviti that is located at the offices of Protiviti as specified above. If you are located in a non-US jurisdiction, please note that you will be transferring your Personal Information to the United States and other jurisdictions that may not provide an equivalent level of data protection to the laws in your home country.

#### **Collections and Uses of Personal Information**

When you use or register with the Site, we may ask for certain Personal Information. The categories of Personal Information we may request include your name, your job title, your company's name and industry sector, your company's location (country, state and zip code) and your contact information (email and phone number). Depending on the nature of your inquiry or activities on the Site, we may also obtain information about your professional interests through white papers or newsletters you request, as well as professional interests that you specifically describe to us. Providing Personal Information is necessary for performance of the services and functionalities offered by the Site. If you decline to provide the requisite Personal Information, we may not be able to process your inquiry or other requests. 

The Site also utilizes cookies to track your online activities, including your registration, submissions, and information requests, in accordance with applicable law. Cookies are files placed on your computer by a website server. Cookies on this Site do not collect Personal Information, but we do track your online activities and may link that information with Personal Information you have provided us through online registration. Your web browser may be set to accept cookies automatically, but can be changed to decline them. The Help section of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to set your browser to prevent accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie or how to disable cookies altogether. Please note that if you decline to accept cookies, then when and if you choose to download materials from the Site, you may be required to register each time you download materials from the Site.

We use Personal Information and other data collected through the Site to register you with the Site and to otherwise provide you with requested information or services. We may also from time to time use your Personal Information to send you automated email messages or marketing materials regarding our services. These email messages may contain web beacons and other features that help us make sure that you received and were able to open the message. You may opt out of receiving such marketing email messages at any time by sending a message with "unsubscribe" in the subject line to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#17676572717265727974726457676578637e617e637e3974787a), or by following the instructions in any marketing communication.

#### **Disclosures of Personal Information**

As described in Section 4 of the [Terms of Use](https://www.protiviti.com/US-en/terms-use), Protiviti may disclose Personal Information to third parties. The disclosure to third parties would occur in the following circumstances:

  1. We may disclose Personal Information to our affiliates in your local jurisdiction or other locations as necessary or appropriate to provide the service you request, to contact you in connection with service offerings, or for other legitimate business purposes;
  2. We may disclose information to companies and individuals we employ to perform business functions and services on our behalf. Such functions may include hosting our Web servers, analyzing data, providing legal, accounting and marketing services, and providing other support services. All such parties will be under obligation to maintain the security and confidentiality of the Personal Information, and to process the data in accordance with our instructions; or
  3. We may disclose Personal Information to the extent necessary or appropriate to government agencies, advisors, and other third parties in order to comply with applicable laws, or if such action is necessary to protect the rights or property of Protiviti or its affiliated companies.

#### **Collection and Use of Other Information**

“ **Other Information** ” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an identifiable individual. We may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including:

  * **Through your browser or device** : Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, and Internet browser type and version.  We use this information to ensure that the Site functions properly.
  * **Using cookies** :  Cookies are pieces of information stored on the computer that you are using.  Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on the Site, pages visited, registrations, submissions, demographics, information requests, language preferences, and other traffic data.  We use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, and to personalize your experience. We also gather statistical information about use of the Site to enhance its functionality, understand how it is used and assist us with resolving questions about it.  We may also use cookies and other technologies in online advertising campaigns to track responses to our ads.

If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, most browsers allow you to automatically decline cookies, or be given the choice of declining or accepting a particular cookie (or cookies) from a particular site. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the Site.

  * **Using pixel tags and** **other similar technologies** : Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used to, among other things, track the actions of Site users and email recipients, market our services to you, measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about Site usage and response rates.
  * **Analytics**. We use third-party analytics providers such as Google Analytics, and Inspectlet on the Site.  Google Analytics uses cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use of the Services and report on activities and trends.  Google Analytics may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources.  You can learn about Google’s practices by going to [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), and opt out by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. We have also engaged Inspectlet to analyze the activities of visitors to this Site, and Inspectlet’s authorized use of cookies and other tracking technologies enable it to have access to Personal Information of visitors to this Site. Such access to and use of Personal Information by Inspectlet is governed by Inspectlet’s Privacy Policy, available at <https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy>. We also use Marketo, a third party marketing automation vendor. To opt out of Marketo, please visit <http://legal.marketo.com/privacy/>
  * **IP Address** :  Your IP Address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider.  An IP Address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses the Site, along with the time of the visit and the pages visited. We use IP Addresses for purposes such as calculating usage levels, diagnosing server problems, and administering the Site. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP Address.

Please note that we may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose.

#### **Retargeting​**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads regarding our services when you access and use other websites, based on information relating to your use of the Site. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through use of pixel tags). By utilizing the Site, you consent to the use of cookie or other tracking technologies to serve you retargeted advertising.

If you would like more information about opting out of this advertising in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Privacy Policy or this type of advertising, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and <http://www.aboutads.info/>.

#### **Third Party Services**

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site or service to which the Site links.

#### **Personal Data Security and Confidentiality**

#### We use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures designed to protect Personal Information within our organization. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us in accordance with the _“Contact Us”_ section below.

#### **Personal Data Access and Correction**

Protiviti will provide access to, update and amend, and/or delete the Personal Information in accordance with applicable law. You can request access to, and have the opportunity to update and amend your Personal Information, and, you can exercise the other rights acknowledged by applicable data protection legislation, including, for example, objection to and blocking of the processing of your Personal Information, by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#5b2b293e3d3e293e35383e281b2b29342f322d322f3275383436) or by sending a letter to Attn: Database Management, Protiviti Inc., 2884 Sand Hill Road, Menlo Park, California 94025. For security reasons, Protiviti reserves the right to take steps to authenticate the identity of the requesting party before providing access to Personal Information in accordance with this section of the Privacy Policy.

#### **Revisions to the Policy**

If we change this Policy we will post any updates here for your review. If we change material terms in this Policy, we will provide notice of the revised policy for 30 days on the home page at [www.protiviti.com](http://www.protiviti.com/) with a link back to this page. We will also take other steps as necessary depending on the nature of the changes, including obtaining your consent where required by local data protection laws, or providing you with the opportunity to delete your Personal Information.

#### **EU-U.S. and SWISS-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework Participation for European Client Engagement Data**

Protiviti Inc. in the U.S. (the "Protiviti US") participates in the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks (the "Frameworks"). Protiviti US’s participation in the Frameworks applies to personal data received in the U.S. from the European Union (“EU”) and Switzerland (“Swiss”) about our corporate clients' personnel, customers and vendors (collectively, "European Client Engagement Data"). We are committed to subjecting such European Client Engagement Data to the Frameworks, including its Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability to the extent applicable to Protiviti US as a processor acting on behalf of our corporate clients. To learn more about the Frameworks, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield List [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome).

#### **European Client Engagement Data Collection, Use, and Disclosure**

We operate as a processor acting on behalf of our corporate clients regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of European Client Engagement Data and we process European Client Engagement Data that our corporate clients submit to our services in accordance with their instructions. If you are an employee at, or customer or vendor of, our corporate clients, please consult the privacy policies of that entity for information about its privacy practices.

#### **Rights of EU and Swiss Data Subjects under the Frameworks**

If you are an EU or Swiss data subject, you have the right to access your own European Client Engagement Data subject to certain limitations, such as where the legitimate rights of other persons would be infringed or where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate.  Please note that because Protiviti US personnel may have limited ability to access European Client Engagement Data our clients provide to us as part of our services, if you wish to request access, to limit use, or to limit disclosure, please contact us as described below and provide the name of the corporate client who submitted your data to us. We will refer your request to that corporate client, and will support them as needed in responding to your request.

#### **Choices of EU and Swiss Data Subjects**

We operate as a processor acting on behalf of our corporate clients and, as such, do not use or disclose European Client Engagement Data in a manner that is subject to choice requirements under the Frameworks.

#### **Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability under the Frameworks**

In compliance with the Frameworks, Protiviti commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of European Client Engagement Data. Individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Frameworks policy should first contact us as specified below. In addition, please contact us as specified below if you have any questions, need access to your European Client Engagement Data, or otherwise need assistance. We remain responsible for our collection, use and disclosure of European Client Engagement Data in accordance with the Frameworks. We also are responsible for third party agents that are processing European Client Engagement Data on our behalf, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose European Client Engagement Data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved concern about European Client Engagement Data that we have not addressed satisfactorily, we have committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU Data Protection Authorities and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) to serve as our independent dispute resolution bodies for the Frameworks. We are also subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission with respect to the Frameworks. In addition, under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website (available [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)), EU and Swiss residents may invoke binding arbitration for non-monetary issues when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

#### **Contact Us**

Please contact us here [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#e5b5978c9384869cc8b68d8c808981a5b5978a918c938c918ccb868a88) if you have any questions, wish to exercise your rights of access, or seek other assistance related to our participation in the Frameworks as described above.

#### This Policy is effective as of October 23, 2017. If you have any questions about our website privacy policies, please contact us at:

#### **Mailing Address**

Privacy Office  
Protiviti Inc.  
2884 Sand Hill Road   
Menlo Park, California 94025  
+1.650.234.6000 

**Email Address**    
[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#afdbcaccc7c1c6cccec381dcdadfdfc0dddbefdfddc0dbc6d9c6dbc681ccc0c2)
